<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AWS on tecRacer Chef</title><link>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/categories/aws.html</link><description>Recent content in AWS on tecRacer Chef</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tecracer-chef.github.io/categories/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Restrict AWS Marketplace offerings with private Marketplace</title><link>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2023/04/restrict-aws-marketplace-offerings-with-private-marketplace.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2023/04/restrict-aws-marketplace-offerings-with-private-marketplace.html</guid><description>&lt;p>People are constantly stumbling over the AWS Marketplace and their more than 30,000 public offerings. Restricting such a massive amount of products is mainly done with the necessary internal AWS Marketplace policy that you find in a document in document management systems like AWS WorkDocs.
What would you say about better restricting the public AWS Marketplace with a private Marketplace?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Arm your GitHub Actions Runners using AWS Graviton</title><link>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2023/03/arm-your-github-actions-runners-using-aws-graviton.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2023/03/arm-your-github-actions-runners-using-aws-graviton.html</guid><description>GitHub does not support any ARM GitHub Actions Runner. So what now? Build it within your AWS environment!
The results are pretty cool: You have full control over the Runners and have no more time constraints like long-running workflows that consume Runners usage minutes.
I will guide you through the basics of creating an AWS EC2 instance and installing the minimum requirements on the OS for having a running GitHub Actions Runner.</description></item><item><title>FSx for NetApp ONTAP Manageability Options</title><link>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2023/01/fsx-for-netapp-ontap-manageability-options.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2023/01/fsx-for-netapp-ontap-manageability-options.html</guid><description>&lt;p>While Amazon FSx for NetApp ONTAP (FSxN) seems relatively easy on the AWS level, it is vastly more powerful if you pick another way to manage it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post will look at a quick run-down across the AWS Web Console, NetApp&amp;rsquo;s BlueXP, various APIs, and the CLI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using AWS mac1/mac2 Instances with Test Kitchen</title><link>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2022/12/using-aws-mac1/mac2-instances-with-test-kitchen.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2022/12/using-aws-mac1/mac2-instances-with-test-kitchen.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Everybody who had to write software or work with configuration management for Apple knows of the problems to get access to test machines. AWS does offer both Intel- and M1-based Mac instances now and with &lt;code>kitchen-ec2&lt;/code> v3.15.0 it is finally possible to use them in your existing workflow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dedicated Hosts with Test Kitchen</title><link>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2022/12/dedicated-hosts-with-test-kitchen.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2022/12/dedicated-hosts-with-test-kitchen.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes, you need to deploy software for tests with special licensing terms. To solve this, AWS offers Dedicated Instances and Dedicated Hosts - and now you can use them with &lt;a href="https://kitchen.ci">Test Kitchen 3.14&lt;/a> in your developer workflows.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Test-Kitchen on AWS (2022 edition)</title><link>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2022/11/test-kitchen-on-aws-2022-edition.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2022/11/test-kitchen-on-aws-2022-edition.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Test-Kitchen is a tool to manage your test machine lifecycle, similar to HashiCorp Vagrant. While it has been developed with Chef in mind, it can be used with any development tool to test on new machines every time you change your code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As this tool continues to evolve and many examples are outdated, today I will give you some small snippets to reuse and get going quickly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Logging Amazon FSx for NetApp ONTAP</title><link>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2022/04/logging-amazon-fsx-for-netapp-ontap.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2022/04/logging-amazon-fsx-for-netapp-ontap.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I spent a lot of time using the exciting new member of the FSx family. One detail made working with it a bit unpleasant, though - the lack of log files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post details how to create a custom integration into CloudWatch Logs and make ONTAP audit logs visible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Testing Terraform with InSpec (Part 1)</title><link>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2021/10/testing-terraform-with-inspec-part-1.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2021/10/testing-terraform-with-inspec-part-1.html</guid><description>While Infrastructure-as-Code slowly becomes omnipresent, many of the communicated advantages of the approach stay mostly unrealized. Sure, code style checks (linting) and even automated documentation get more common every month. But one of the cornerstones often gets ignore: testing.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see which types of code testing are available and how to do it without writing too much code.
The promise of the Infrastructure-as-Code (short: IaC) movement is to handle infrastructure just as if it was a program.</description></item><item><title>CDK Infrastructure Testing - Part 2a - Implement Unit, Integration and Application Test for CDK Infrastructure and an EC2 Web Server Application</title><link>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/cdk-cit-part2a/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/cdk-cit-part2a/</guid><description>&lt;p>With CDK you create Infrastructure as Code - IaC. You can automate the test for the IaC code.
The three test tastes -Unit, Integration and Application- should work closely together. Here I show you how. It is like the three steps of coffee tasting: 1 smell, 2 Taste, 3 Feel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CIT - Build CDK Infrastructure Testing - Part 1 - Terratest and the Integrated Integration</title><link>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2021/05/cit-build-cdk-infrastructure-testing-part-1-terratest-and-the-integrated-integration.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2021/05/cit-build-cdk-infrastructure-testing-part-1-terratest-and-the-integrated-integration.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="heading">&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>TL;DR You don`t need a DSL to do easy integration testing. With CDK available in go, infrastructure test can be programmed with GO packages easily.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mit allen verbunden Teil 2</title><link>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2019/01/mit-allen-verbunden-teil-2.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tecracer-chef.github.io/2019/01/mit-allen-verbunden-teil-2.html</guid><description>Infrastrukturtest des Transit Gateway mit kitchen und Inspec
Transit Gateway (What is a Transit Gateway? – Amazon Virtual Private Cloud) ist ein neuer AWS Service, der VPC Peering komplett ablösen kann. Zusätzlich kann damit auch ein „transitives&amp;quot; Peering gebaut werden. Das heißt, anders als bei einer VPC Peering Verbindung, die immer nur zwei VPCs miteinander verbindet, werden hier alle Netze miteinander verbunden. Das lohnt es sich genau zu testen! Diesen Test will ich hier möglichst vollautomatisiert aufbauen.</description></item></channel></rss>